rehlat.com 2019-05-01

# Privacy Policy | Rehlat

**Information collection and use**

We take our responsibilities regarding the protection of your personal information very seriously. This policy explains how we use personal information that we may obtain from you. By using our website www.rehlat.com, henceforth referred to as “Rehlat” which also comprises of the mobile site, smartphone app platforms such as iOS, Android, Windows (all together referred to as “site”), you consent to this use.

This privacy policy does not apply to the websites of our business partners, corporate affiliates or to any other third parties, even if their websites are linked to the site. We recommend you to review the respective privacy statements of the other parties with whom you interact.

When you use services provided on Rehlat’s website and/or mobile application, you will be asked to provide certain information such as your name, contact details, and/or your debit/credit card details. All credit/debit cards details and personally identifiable information will NOT be stored, sold, shared, rented or leased to any third parties.

**Information we obtain**

  * Personal information
  * Transactional information
  * Booking information
  * Other information like preferences, destination choices, etc.

**Information usage**

  * By default, a log in ID is created on Rehlat when you book with us. The log in is created using your Name and Email id which you provide for booking.
  * To fulfill our agreement with you, including processing your flight, reservation and any other booking, sending you your itinerary, or contacting you if there is a problem with your reservation.
  * To register you with our website/mobile application and administer our website services where you have registered to receive these. You can unsubscribe from these services by contacting us.
  * To answer any queries which you may send to us by e-mail.

**For direct marketing purposes, as set out in detail below.**

  * We need to know the names of all the passengers travelling or the names related to the reservation concerned. If you are booking a flight or reservation on behalf of someone else, you must obtain their consent to use their personal information. We proceed on the basis that you have obtained the aforementioned consent.
  * To conduct bookings, ticketing and payment transactions for the services available on the site.
  * To personalize your experience and give you better service: (your information helps us to better respond to your individual needs)
  * To improve the user friendliness of the site; (we continually strive to improve the site offerings based on the information we receive from you)
  * To improve customer service (your information helps us to more effectively respond to your customer service requests and support needs) website traffic analysis
  * To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site features
  * To send emails, SMS and other communications for providing services, responding to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions.
  * To respond to queries of the authorities in regard to your accessing of the site and services availed by you.
  * Automatic Logging of Session Data

**Note: However, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your Rehlat log in passwords, and your site membership account information. Please be very careful, responsible, and alert with this information, especially whenever you’re online.**

**How do we use your personal information?**

Information you provide or that is obtained by us will be used by us to enable us to review, develop and improve the services which we offer and provide you and other customers (via mail, email, telephone or otherwise) with information about new products and services and special offers we think you will find valuable. We may also inform you about new products and services and special offers of selected third parties, if, at the time of registration, you have opted for receiving the Rehlat newsletter or updates.

**Who do we share your information with?**

  * To our customer support offices in the network.
  * To trustworthy third parties that we use for the provision of certain services, such as enabling our customers to get baggage insurance (BRB), telecommunication services (Ooredoo), or other travel related services to offer hassle free travel experience.
  * To customs and/or immigration departments or other regulatory authorities in your country of departure and/or destination in order to comply with the law in those countries.
  * To the third party organizations involved in credit card authorization.
  * If we have a duty to do so or if the law allows us to do so.
  * To our employees and agents to do any of the above on our behalf, now or in the future.
  * To the companies within our corporate family and with our parent company and corporate affiliates. This sharing enables us to provide you with information about products and services, both travel-related and other, which might interest you. To the extent that our parent company and corporate affiliates have access to your information, they will follow practices that are at least as restrictive as the practices described in this privacy policy. They also will comply with applicable laws governing the transmission of promotional communications and, at a minimum, give you an opportunity in any commercial email they send to choose not to receive such email messages in the future.

If you choose not to provide certain personal information we request, you will still be able to visit our site but you may be unable to access certain options or services.

**Personal information data transfer**

In the course of undertaking the activities specified in this privacy policy, we may transfer personal information to countries which do not have data protection laws or to countries where your privacy and other fundamental rights will not be protected as extensively. We will transfer information only for the purpose of fulfilling/providing the services you have requested from us, in order to fulfill a contract with a third party for your benefit, or to disclose information which we are required to do by law or requested from us by a regulator.

**Data we collect from Mobile Apps-**

When you install and use Rehlat mobile app, we collect the following information

1. Information that you provide to Rehlat App, such as when you create your Rehlat account or Social Sign In via Facebook or Google- First Name, Last Name, Email ID, Phone Number.

2. Information created when you use our services such as

  * Personal information, which includes your email address, name, phone number, device ID and IP address.
  * Transactional information, such as itinerary details
  * Booking information, such as travel destination and dates
  * Other information, such as your browsing activity on the website and mobile app

3. In addition to the above mentioned information we collect and use some information that we collect automatically and some information with your permission when you use our mobile app.

How we use the information for Mobile apps-

  * To fulfill our agreement with you, including processing your flight bookings and any other reservations, sending you your itinerary, or contacting you if there is a problem with your reservation.
  * To register you with our website/mobile application and administer our website services where you have registered to receive these. You can unsubscribe from these services by contacting us.
  * To answer any queries which you may send to us by e-mail.
  * Device UDI

Each mobile app also sends us the device's unique device identifier (or "UDI"), a sequence of numbers or characters that are unique to your mobile device. We use this only on the first opening of the mobile app so that we can confirm to our advertising networks the number of downloads resulting from clicks on their respective banner ads and other marketing tools.

  * IP address

We collect IP Address to help us block cyber-attacks from certain locations which may cause irreplaceable damages to our Website, Apps & Systems.

  * GPS Location after taking your permission

When you use a mobile app, you can choose to allow access to your current location – provided by your mobile device using GPS or similar technologies – in order to identify nearby hotels or airports. If you choose to allow access, this location data may be collected anonymously as part of search requests logged by our servers. You can switch off the mobile app’s access to your location at any time through your phone settings menu. This might however restrict usage of any location-dependent services or options available on our mobile app.

  * Read SMS Automatically after taking your permission

We read SMS with your permission in order to complete the OTP authentication process with ease.

We use the automatically collected information to understand user specific issues, fix device and location specific bugs and to communicate updates like flight delay, schedule change and other important information for your convenience. Sometimes we may send this information to our trusted partner service providers which helps us to provide better understanding of the service and user experience which is specific to certain users or devices. We collect information about mobile app functionality that you access and use. This allows us to identify those areas of the mobile app that are of interest to our customers so that we can refine and continuously improve the mobile app. You always have the ability to control what information a mobile app sends to us. You can exercise this control either by changing the settings of the mobile app under its setting menu or changing the settings of your mobile device. Alternatively, you can remove the mobile app from your mobile device entirely and access our services through our website.

**Cookies Policy**

There is a technology called "cookies" which may be used by us to provide you with customized information from Rehlat websites or mobile application. A cookie is an element of data that a website or mobile application can send to your browser, which may then store it on your system. Cookies allow us to understand who has seen which pages and advertisements, to determine how frequently particular pages are visited and to determine the most popular areas of our website. Cookies also allow us to make Rehlat websites or mobile application more user-friendly by, for example, allowing us to take you to the language site of last use, so that we can give you a better experience when you return to our website. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies. You do not have to accept cookies, and you should read the information that came with your browser software to see how you can set it up to notify you when you receive a cookie, so you can decide whether to accept it.

The website policies and Terms & Conditions may be changed or updated occasionally to meet the requirements and standards. Therefore customers’ are encouraged to frequently visit these sections in order to be updated about the changes on the website. Modifications will be effective on the day they are posted.

For any other queries, enquiries, and clarification on data/information collection, protection, and usage, or if you wish to unsubscribe from certain notifications, please mail to [dop@rehlat.com](http://dop@rehlat.com/). Our Data Protection team would respond within 24 Business Hours.

**Note: You can also opt out of notifications by using unsubscribe/block options on the respective channels.**
